[Speaker A] Welcome, everyone, to this second E round
[Speaker A] profile. I'm Riccardo Rossi and I'm here,
[Speaker A] as usual, with Federico Marini. Hi,
[Speaker A] Federico, how are you? And today our guest
[Speaker A] is Sharon Machlis. Hi, Sharon, how are
[Speaker A] you?
[Speaker B] Hi. Nice to see you.
[Speaker A] Okay. Sharon is director of Editorial Data
[Speaker A] and Analytics at IDG Communication, and
[Speaker A] she's also author of Practical R for Mass
[Speaker A] Communication and Journalism. Did I say it
[Speaker A] right, Sharon?
[Speaker B] Yes, you did. Thank you.
[Speaker A] Okay, great. Great to have you here
[Speaker A] chatting with us. And she's also, of
[Speaker A] course, one of the ERA 2020 keynote
[Speaker A] speakers for the virtual conference in
[Speaker A] June. So my first question is, does
[Speaker A] journalism need to be data? Journalism
[Speaker A] needs to be data driven today. Or let's
[Speaker A] say at least to what extent and what role
[Speaker A] for R in this?
[Speaker B] Yeah, some does and some doesn't. You
[Speaker B] know, every story doesn't need to have
[Speaker B] data, but a lot of stories need to have
[Speaker B] data. And good data. Journalists
[Speaker B] understand that the data isn't the whole
[Speaker B] story. You still want to talk to people
[Speaker B] and get context and get what we call color
[Speaker B] and, you know, quotes from people.
[Speaker B] Understanding how the data affects people.
[Speaker B] That's the difference between journalism
[Speaker B] and just data analysis. But there is an
[Speaker B] awful lot of journalism where having the
[Speaker B] data really makes your story stronger.