[speaker_0] Welcome, everyone, uh, to this, uh, second
[speaker_0] IRAM profile. I'm Ricardo Rossi and I'm
[speaker_0] here as usual with Federico Marini. Hi,
[speaker_0] Federico.
[speaker_1] Hi.
[speaker_0] And today, uh, our guest is Sharon
[speaker_0] Machlis. Hi, Sharon. How are you?
[speaker_2] Hi, nice to see you.
[speaker_0] Okay. Sharon, uh, is a- is director of
[speaker_0] editorial data and analytics at IDG
[speaker_0] Communication, and she's also author of
[speaker_0] Practical R for Mass Communication and
[speaker_0] Journalisms. Did I say it right, Sharon?
[speaker_2] Yes, you did. Thank you.
[speaker_0] Okay, great. Great to have you here
[speaker_0] chatting with us. And she's also, of
[speaker_0] course, one of the IRAM 2020 keynote
[speaker_0] speakers for the virtual conference in
[speaker_0] June. So my first question is, does
[speaker_0] journalisms need to be... data journalisms
[speaker_0] needs to be data-driven today, or let's
[speaker_0] say, at least to what extent? And what
[speaker_0] role for R in this?
[speaker_2] Yeah, some does and some doesn't. You
[speaker_2] know, every story doesn't need to have
[speaker_2] data, but a lot of stories need to have
[speaker_2] data. And good data journalists understand
[speaker_2] that the data isn't the whole story. You
[speaker_2] still wanna talk to people and get context
[speaker_2] and get what we call color, you know,
[speaker_2] quotes from people, understanding how the
[speaker_2] data affects people. That's the difference
[speaker_2] between journalism and just data analysis.
[speaker_2] But there's an awful lot of journalism
[speaker_2] where having the data really makes your
[speaker_2] story stronger.